

# Email: Joeluna17@outlook.com

Phone: 903-422-2686

GitHub: https://github.com/joeluna17

LinkedIn:
<a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/joseph-luna-dev/">https://www.linkedin.com/in/joseph-luna-dev/</a>

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**



## Joseph Luna

### Senior Full Stack Developer

Innovative, task-driven professional with 5 years of experience in web development. Equipped with a successful record in consistency in identifying and providing technological needs for companies that scale. Proficiency in developing data schemas and user interfaces from design to implementation. Troubleshooting simple and complex issues and implementing trusted fixes.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

Senior Full Stack Developer / Team Lead Zilis LLC – Argyle, TX (Remote) 03/2020 – Present

- Helped company initiate and implement Agile development workflow.
- Worked daily with team leveraging Agile development workflow and ceremonies (Daily Standup, Grooming, Retrospective).
- Worked in two-week sprints with team to complete assigned work items and followed coding best practices as well as peer code reviews via Azure DevOps.
- Developed with git versioning workflow via Azure DevOps.
- Maintenance and development in existing Angular 8 / Dotnet Core 3.1 monolithic application (Typescript / C#).
- Leverage NGRX for state management and RXJS for state and component subscriptions.
- Modified and created new features for Angular 8 application as well as provide oversight on complete redesign and code implementation.
- Implemented i18n translations using ngx-translate.
- Modified and create new backend controllers and endpoints to access third party services via REST and SOAP.
- Implemented logging from DNC backend to Azure Application Insights for UAT and Production environments.
- Created schemas and tables in SQL Azure DB for new applications and features (SQL server and SQL Data Studio).
- Created two Express backends in Node.js that connected to Azure hosted databases leveraging Knex.js for DB connections and migrations (multiple environments). Backends also connect to third-party services.
- Facilitate login and account creation services using Jason Web Tokens (JWT) for authorization and bcrypt for password hashing during creation / authentication.
- Writing DB queries using Knex.js to retrieve requested data. (C.R.U.D).
- Create builds for Express applications using Azure pipelines deployment scripts for development and production with Webpack. (Optimize builds).
- Test endpoints using Postman.
- Created Six React frontends utilizing React Bootstrap styling library, Styled Components, React-Router, and many other third-party packages. (JS / TS)
- Utilized functional reusable component architecture and leveraged hooks for state.

- Utilized Redux and Redux Thunk for application state management and async services.
- Utilized Redux DevTools for state debugging.
- Utilized axios for http services.
- Initialized component library via npm leveraging Storyboard for creating reusable components in isolation.
- Implemented i18n translations using react-intl library.
- · Implemented GraphQL in some frontend applications using Apollo Client.
- Integrated Azure Active Directory for employee login for some frontend applications.
- Monitored and maintained Azure App Services as well app production support.
- Maintenance and development in WordPress. (PHP)
- Created Blog site in WordPress.
- Assist junior developers and contractors with code familiarity and blockers during development.
- Assist onboarding and architecture overview for new hires.
- · Assist with developer interviews for technical feedback.

#### **Software Engineer**

NCR - Fort Worth, TX

01/2020 - 03/2020

- Worked daily with team leveraging Agile development workflow and ceremonies (Daily Standup, Grooming, Retrospective).
- Worked in two-week sprints with team to complete assigned work items and followed coding best practices as well as peer code reviews via Jira.
- Developed with git versioning workflow via Source Tree.
- Worked closely with QA to resolve code remediation.
- Support and development in Java / ASP.net monolithic application (Java / C#).
- Modified and created new features in Angular JS application for Backoffice dashboards and reporting UI (JavaScript).
- Modified and created new stored procedures in SQL for Backoffice reporting.
- Worked in multiple development environments.
- Worked with team to troubleshoot and research production errors and provide hotfix solutions.
- Provide deployment support for new features into production via Jenkins pipeline.

#### **Owner/Operator**

The Garage Door Co Plus - Greenville, TX

03/2014 - 01/2020

- Manage day to day operations in both office and field work.
- · Sales and Customer Relations via face to face, online, phone, and email.
- Design and deployment of project planning and schematics.
- Employee scheduling and assuring adherence to project timelines.
- Heavy MS Excel use for form creations and data tracking.
- Creation and deployment of business website via yahoo business services.

#### Web Analyst

Innovation First Labs – Greenville, TX

04/2013 - 03/2014

- Maintained and create products via Magento using design and hardcode assets on Consumer/Reseller Sites for USA, Canada, and UK.
- Coded new products and pages in CMS block/static block via Magento using CSS3, HTML 5, and JavaScript.
- Designed and deployment of responsive weekly email blast via Mail Chimp coded in HTML table layout and inline CSS3.
- Collaborated with Marketing, Design, and Legal department personnel for project execution.
- Created workflow tool program in C# to aide in product fulfillment.
- Account Facilitator for Walmart US duties include store replenishment and maintenance via VPN and onsite execution.
- · Planogram design, maintenance, and distribution for Walmart accounts.
- Refined process for in store product placement/sales execution via Crossmark for Walmart account.
- Data entry for Walmart product creation and maintenance via Partners online Portal and Retail Link.
- Hardware and peripheral setup for new hire and existing employees.
- Software setup (Office 365, AutoCAD, Epicor, etc.) and updates for new hire and existing employees.
- Heavy use of Excel tables and pivot tables.

#### **COURSES & TRAINING**

- Treehouse Self paced learning platform for IOS, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, PHP
- Udemy Self paced learning platform for IOS, C#
- BloomTech formally (Lambda) Full Stack Web Development.

#### **Education**

- High School Greenville High School, 2001
- DeVry University Irving Texas Bachelor's in Computer Engineering Technology 2009 – 2012 (Senior year remaining)